<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on INBO Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on INBO Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Books and articles on statistics</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/statistics/</guid>
      <description>McElreath (2015): Statistical Rethinking is an introduction to applied Bayesian data analysis, aimed at PhD students and researchers in the natural and social sciences. This audience has had some calculus and linear algebra, and one or two joyless undergraduate courses in statistics. I&amp;rsquo;ve been teaching applied statistics to this audience for about a decade now, and this book has evolved from that experience. The book teaches generalized linear multilevel modeling (GLMMs) from a Bayesian perspective, relying on a simple logical interpretation of Bayesian probability and maximum entropy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific computing and data handling workflows</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/computing/</guid>
      <description>This page lists selected literature and online resources. Some are related to existing tutorial pages, while others are not. They are supposed to be of high interest to this site&amp;rsquo;s users.
Several of the resources were added based on an inspiring talk by Julia Lowndes at the SAFRED conference, Brussels, 27 Feb 2018.
Overviews  Wilson et al. (2017): set of good computing practices that every researcher can adopt British Ecological Society (2014): planning the data life cycle; creating, processing, documenting, preserving, sharing &amp;amp; reusing data Cooper &amp;amp; Hsing (2017): file organisation, workflow documentation, code reproducibility and readability, writing reproducible reports, version control and code archiving Ibanez et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acquiring the skills</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/skills/</guid>
      <description>This page lists selected literature and online resources. Some are related to existing tutorial pages, while others are not. They are supposed to be of high interest to this site&amp;rsquo;s users.
Several of the resources were added based on an inspiring talk by Julia Lowndes at the SAFRED conference, Brussels, 27 Feb 2018.
These resources focus on the learning and teaching aspect, while they often also give an overview of scientific computing workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing and communicating</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/communicating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/communicating/</guid>
      <description>This page lists selected literature and online resources. Some are related to existing tutorial pages, while others are not. They are supposed to be of high interest to this site&amp;rsquo;s users.
Several of the resources were added based on an inspiring talk by Julia Lowndes at the SAFRED conference, Brussels, 27 Feb 2018.
Sharing data  Ellis &amp;amp; Leek (2017): guidelines for providing data to a scientist / statistician: provide raw data, format consistently, include metadata &amp;amp; preprocessing steps Wilkinson et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The discipline of open science</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/open_science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/open_science/</guid>
      <description>This page lists selected literature and online resources. Some are related to existing tutorial pages, while others are not. They are supposed to be of high interest to this site&amp;rsquo;s users.
Several of the resources were added based on an inspiring talk by Julia Lowndes at the SAFRED conference, Brussels, 27 Feb 2018.
These resources focus on the discipline as a whole, its perception, principles ,etc., while they often also give an overview of scientific computing workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create tutorial</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/create_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/create_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Introduction First of all, thanks to consider making a new tutorial! By providing a tutorial, you are actively supporting your colleagues and the wider community and making work more efficient.
In this page, the roadmap towards a new tutorial will be explained.
Writing a tutorial Each tutorial is setup in a subfolder of the content/tutorials folder. Within this folder, different files and formats may exist as you create them, but a file with the name index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R voor beginners</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_beginners/</guid>
      <description>De opleiding R voor beginners bestaat uit 4 workshops en is bedoeld voor mensen die nog nooit met R gewerkt hebben. In de workshops wordt het materiaal in de handleidingen al doende uitgelegd, en afgewisseld met oefeningen. Na elke workshop wordt er altijd een huistaak aangeboden, die op vrijwillige basis ingediend kan worden, en van feedback voorzien.
Les 1: R en RStudio Introductie tot R en Rstudio
 Uitleg van alle vensters in Rstudio, en overlopen van de user installation instructions Werken met projecten Coding basics in R Packages installeren en laden Vectoren en dataframes Inlezen van gegevens in verschillende formaten  Handleiding R en RStudio</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INLA workshops</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_inla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_inla/</guid>
      <description>These workshops are a follow-up of the course on &amp;ldquo;Spatial, temporal and spatial-temporal models using R-INLA&amp;rdquo; by Alain Zuur and Elena Ieno (Highland Statistics Ltd.). The main goal is the get people using R-INLA with their own data in a workshop setting so they can tap into the knowledge of others. The workshops are not a copy of the Highstat course but elaborate certain topics. We also introduce the inlatools and inlabru.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git(hub) introduction</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/git_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/git_introduction/</guid>
      <description>At INBO, people do write code and require version control. As git is not the most straightforward environment to work with for non-IT specialists, we try to define our own sub-ecosystem with relevant practices and an achievable workflow.
To introduce the concept of version control with Git and Github, a separate git course website is available here.
The git course provides an introduction on main terminology of Git based on 5 important tasks:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMM surface waters - quality data</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/vmm_surface_waters_quality_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/vmm_surface_waters_quality_data/</guid>
      <description>OPGELET: deze databank is alleen raadpleegbaar voor INBO-medewerkers, niet voor externen. Externen kunnen gebruik maken van het VMM-geoloket waterkwaliteit.
Het INBO krijgt jaarlijks een (gedeeltelijke) kopie van de waterkwaliteitsdatabank van de Vlaamse Milieumaatschappij (VMM). De kopie omvat fysicochemische metingen en kwaliteitsindexen uit het VMM-meetnet oppervlaktewaters. Deze en andere waterkwaliteitsgevens zijn rechtstreeks opvraagbaar via het VMM-geoloket waterkwaliteit, maar de lokale kopie laat een veel vlottere raadpleging toe wanneer analyse van een groter aantal meetpunten gewenst is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headers and navigation in R code</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_script_sections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_script_sections/</guid>
      <description>Introduction R code can become elaborate and consequently unclear or difficult to navigate. Yet, it is possible to introduce headers and navigate through them.
Creating sections manually To create a header of a section, different methods can be applied. Any comment line which includes at least four trailing dashes (-), equal signs (=), or hash tags (#) automatically creates a code section.
# 1. Header 1 #### # 2. Header 2 ---- # 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s create an interactive map!</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_create_leaflet_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_create_leaflet_map/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The required packages are leaflet and sp.
library(leaflet) library(sp) Dummy data Let&amp;rsquo;s create a dumy data.frame to play around, i.e. the three locations of INBO:
names &amp;lt;- c(&amp;#34;VAC HT&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Geraardsbergen&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Linkebeek&amp;#34;) lat &amp;lt;- c(50.865664, 50.760201, 50.767950) lon &amp;lt;- c(4.349944, 3.874300, 4.333044) data &amp;lt;- data.frame(names,lat,lon) We created three points:
plot(data$lon, data$lat) Creating a map We need to convert the data.frame to a SpatialPointsDataFrame:
crs_wgs84 &amp;lt;- CRS(&amp;#34;+init=epsg:4326&amp;#34;) pts &amp;lt;- SpatialPointsDataFrame(data[c(&amp;#34;lon&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;lat&amp;#34;)], data[!(names(data) %in% c(&amp;#34;lon&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;lat&amp;#34;))], proj4string = crs_wgs84) The leaflet package is ideal to create a basic interactive map:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Match scientific names with the GBIF backbone</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_gbif_name_matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_gbif_name_matching/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will explain how you can match a list of &amp;lsquo;scientific names&amp;rsquo; to the GBIF taxonomic backbone
Important is that you have rgbif and inborutils installed and available:
library(tidyverse) # tidyverse library(rgbif) # To Match GBIF library(inborutils) # wrap GBIF api data library(knitr) Read data file containing the scientific names Read file containing the scientific names you want to check against the GBIF taxonomic backbone:
species_list &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;#34;https://raw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using `%&gt;%` pipes in R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_tidyverse_piping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_tidyverse_piping/</guid>
      <description>library(dplyr) How to use piping in R Normally, you would do this:
head(mtcars) ## mpg cyl disp hp drat wt qsec vs am gear carb ## Mazda RX4 21.0 6 160 110 3.90 2.620 16.46 0 1 4 4 ## Mazda RX4 Wag 21.0 6 160 110 3.90 2.875 17.02 0 1 4 4 ## Datsun 710 22.8 4 108 93 3.85 2.320 18.61 1 1 4 1 ## Hornet 4 Drive 21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insync installation</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/user/user_install_insync/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 11:01:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/user/user_install_insync/</guid>
      <description>Insync is a thirth party tool that synchronises files with Google Drive. It has some nice features which are still not available in the sync tools provided by Google. For the remaining of this tutorial, &amp;ldquo;GoogleDrive&amp;rdquo; refers to the sync tools provided by Google.
The problem with GoogleDrive GoogleDrive doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well in combination with RStudio projects or Git projects. We&amp;rsquo;ll illustrate the problem with RStudio. RStudio has a performant auto save functionality, which limits data loss after an unexpected crash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wercker</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/development_wercker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 11:23:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/development_wercker/</guid>
      <description>Set up continuous integration with Wercker There are 2 major steps to set up continuous integration:
 create a wercker.yml file in the package add the application (package) to Wercker.com  To be able to add a package to Wercker, one must have administrator rights on the package repository on Github.
The Wercker test environment can only be set up if the file wercker.yml is commited to the repository, but Wercker is triggered to start checking when the application is added to wercker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using WFS service in R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_wfs_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 16:50:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_wfs_services/</guid>
      <description>What is WFS? In computing, the Open Geospatial Consortium Web Feature Service (WFS) Interface Standard provides an interface allowing requests for geographical features across the web using platform-independent calls. One can think of geographical features as the &amp;ldquo;source code&amp;rdquo; behind a map, whereas the WMS interface or online tiled mapping portals like Google Maps return only an image, which end-users cannot edit or spatially analyze. The XML-based GML furnishes the default payload-encoding for transporting geographic features, but other formats like shapefiles can also serve for transport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming spatial objects</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_transform_crs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 14:52:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_transform_crs/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes we have a layer in one coordinate reference system (CRS) and need to transform it into another coordinate reference system. The first thing we need to do is identifying both coordinate reference systems. Let&amp;rsquo;s create an example and identify the coordinate reference system with proj4string(). We used the coordinates posted on the contact page of NGI.
library(sp) library(leaflet) library(widgetframe) ## Loading required package: htmlwidgets  ngi &amp;lt;- data.frame(x = 650381.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using WMS service in R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_wms_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 12:09:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_wms_services/</guid>
      <description>WMS stands for Web Map Service. The service provides prerendered tiles at different scales. This makes it useful to include them as background images in maps.
wms_grb links to the WMS of the GRB-basiskaart, the Flemish cadastral map. It depicts land parcels, buildings, watercourses, roads and railroads.
wms_ortho contains a mosaic of recent orthophotos made during the winter. The layer Ortho contains the images, the layer Vliegdagcontour detail on the time when the pictures were taken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data wrangling with tidyverse</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_tidyverse_info/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 14:14:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_tidyverse_info/</guid>
      <description>Real life datasources seldom provide data in exactly the format you need for the analysis. Hence most of the time you need to manipulate the data after reading it into R. There are several ways to do this, each with their pros and cons. We highly recommend the tidyverse collection of packages. The command library(tidyverse) will actually load the following packages: ggplot2, dplyr, tidyr, readr, purrr, tibble, stringr and forecats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Kerberos authentication for database connection</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/user/user_install_kerberos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/user/user_install_kerberos/</guid>
      <description>Introduction (shamelessly taken from wikipedia)
Kerberos is a computer network authentication protocol that works on the basis of tickets to allow nodes communicating over a non-secure network to prove their identity to one another in a secure manner.
Windows 2000 and later uses Kerberos as its default authentication method. Many UNIX and UNIX-like operating systems, including FreeBSD, Apple&amp;rsquo;s Mac OS X, Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Oracle&amp;rsquo;s Solaris, IBM&amp;rsquo;s AIX and Z/OS, HP&amp;rsquo;s HP-UX and OpenVMS and others, include software for Kerberos authentication of users or services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Styleguide new git repositories</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/styleguide_repos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 16:02:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/styleguide_repos/</guid>
      <description> Naming  Use lowercase for repository, directory, and file names. For R-related files, use uppercase R.
https://github.com/inbo/data-publication ../tutorials/gis/leaflet-R.Rmd  Use dash (-) to separate words in repository, directory, and file names. Don&amp;rsquo;t use underscores.
.../datasets/bird-tracking-gull-occurrences/mapping/dwc-occurrence.sql   READMEs </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Styleguide R code</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/styleguide_r_code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 16:01:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/styleguide_r_code/</guid>
      <description>Scope This style guide is a recommendation for all R code written for the Research Institute for Nature and Forest (INBO). The goal of this style guide is twofold. First of all applying the guidelines will result in readable code. Secondly, it is much easier to work together on code when everyone is using the same guidelines. It is likely that applying these guidelines will have consequences on the current style used by many R users at INBO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rstudio installation</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/user/user_install_rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 15:43:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/user/user_install_rstudio/</guid>
      <description>Na de eerste installatie  Start Rstudio Kies in het menu Tools -&amp;gt; Global Options In het tabblad General  Pas de Default working directory aan naar de locatie waar je R versie staat (C:/Program Files/R/R-3.x.y) 1 Restore .RData into workspace at startup: uitvinken Save workspace to.RData on exit: Never  In het tabblad Code  Subtab Editing  Insert spaces for tab: aanvinken Tab width: 2 Soft-wrap R source files: aanvinken  Subtab Saving  Default text encoding: UTF-8  Subtab Diagnostics  Alles aanvinken   In het tabblad Appearance  Stel in naar eigen smaak  In het tabblad Packages  CRAN mirror: wijzigen naar Global (CDN) - RStudio  In het tabblad Sweave  Weave Rnw files using: knitr Typeset LaTeX into PDF using: XeLaTex  Klik op OK en herstart RStudio  Configuratie van RStudio na een upgrade van R  Start RStudio Kies in het menu Tools -&amp;gt; Global Options Indien niet de laatste versie vermeld staat bij R version: klik op Change om het aan te passen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R language installation</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/user/user_install_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 15:43:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/user/user_install_r/</guid>
      <description>Na de eerste installatie Bij een nieuwe R installatie hoeft de gebruiker geen bijkomende stappen te ondernemen.
Na elke upgrade Voor onderstaande instructies uit telkens een nieuwe R versie geïnstalleerd werd. Je kan dit, indien gewenst, ook frequenter uitvoeren.
Windows  Zorg dat de computer verbonden is met het internet. Zorg dat er geen enkele R sessie actief is op de computer. Start R x64 via het menu start. Tik het commando update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undo a git commit</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/git_undo_commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 15:31:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/git_undo_commit/</guid>
      <description>Introduction You notice you have done something wrong on your branch. No worries, erroneous commits can be undone or reverted.
First, check your history of commits to see which commits are the faulty ones.
git log --oneline  Example output
b7119f2 Continue doing crazy things 872fa7e Try something crazy a1e8fb5 Make some important changes to hello.py 435b61d Create hello.py 9773e52 Initial import  Git checkout The git checkout command serves three distinct functions: checking out files, checking out commits, and checking out branches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git without internet</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/git_no_internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 15:30:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/git_no_internet/</guid>
      <description>When working off line, two Git tasks cannot be performed: fetching/pulling updates from the server, and pushing changes to the server. All other commands still work.
One can commit changes, branch off, revert and reset changes, the same as when there exists an internet connection.
Example workflow: start offline mode
while(notBored): commit changes add files branch off new features  end offline mode
update master branch
git fetch origin  push changes to the server</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git workflow using the command line</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/git_workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 14:42:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/git_workflow/</guid>
      <description>BEFORE I START WORKING  STEP 1: Update the master branch on my PC to make sure it is aligned with the remote master
git fetch origin git checkout master git merge --ff-only origin/master  STEP 2: Choose your option:
 OPTION 2A: I already have a branch I want to continue working on:
Switch to existing topic branch:
git checkout name_existing_branch git fetch origin git rebase origin/master  OPTION 2B: I&amp;rsquo;ll make a new branch to work with: Create a new topic branch from master(!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handle conflicts</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/git_conflict/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/git_conflict/</guid>
      <description>Fix merge conflict with a pull request You have made some changes to a feature branch. Make a pull request on the server. The standard case of automatic merge is not possible. Push your latest changes from the feature branch to the server.
Locally on your computer:
git fetch origin  Rebase your feature branch with your master
git rebase origin/master  Git will now state that there are merge conflicts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Desktop installation</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:30:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_rstudio/</guid>
      <description>De installatiebestanden voor de stabiele versies zijn beschikbaar via http://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/. De preview versie is beschikbaar via https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/preview/
Windows Nieuwe installatie en upgrade van RStudio RStudio upgraden doe je door de nieuwe versie te installeren over de oude.
 Zorg dat eerst R geïnstalleerd is. Voer het 64-bit installatiebestand uit. Welkom bij de installatie: klik op volgende. Geef de doelmap en klik op volgende. Je mag de standaard gebruiken. Klik op installeren.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rtools installation</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_rtools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:30:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_rtools/</guid>
      <description>Windows Installatie en upgrade De installatiebestanden zijn beschikbaar via https://cloud.r-project.org/bin/windows/Rtools/
Bij een upgrade dient eerst de vorige versie te worden verwijderd.
 Kies Nederlands als taal voor de installatie en klik volgende. Klik volgende. Kies C:\Rtools (standaard) als installatiemap en klik volgende. Kies uit dropdown menu Tools for building R packages from source (standaard) en klik volgende. Vink Add rtools to system path aan en klik volgende. Klik volgende. Klik installeren.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git installation</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_git/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:29:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_git/</guid>
      <description>Windows De installatiebestanden zijn beschikbaar via http://git-scm.com/downloads
 Voer het installatiebestand uit Welkom bij de installatie: klik op Next Aanvaard de licentievoorwaarden door Next te klikken Installeer git in de voorgesteld standaard directory. Gebruik de standaard componenten door Next te klikken Kies use Git from the Windows Command Prompt en klik Next Kies Checkout Windows-style, commit Unix-style line endings en klik Next Kies use Windows&#39; default console window en klik Next Klik op Finish  Afwijkingen t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandoc installation</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_pandoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:28:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_pandoc/</guid>
      <description> Windows Pandoc wordt automatisch geïnstalleerd als je RStudio installeert.
Ubuntu  Kijk op https://github.com/jgm/pandoc/releases wat de laatste versie is. Pas het versienummer in onderstaande code aan en voer ze uit in een terminalvenster
wget https://github.com/jgm/pandoc/releases/download/1.19/pandoc-1.19-1-amd64.deb sudo dpkg -i pandoc-1.19-1-amd64.deb rm pandoc-1.19-1-amd64.deb   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:25:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_r/</guid>
      <description>Windows Installatiebestand beschikbaar via https://cloud.r-project.org/bin/windows/base/
In de onderstaande tekst moet je in R-3.x.y zowel x als y vervangen door een cijfer om zo het huidige versienummer te krijgen. Dus voor versie R-3.0.0 is x = 0 en y = 0.
Nieuwe installatie van R  Voer het bestand R-3.x.y-win.exe uit. Kies Nederlands als taal voor de installatie en klik op OK. klik op Volgende. Aanvaard de licentievoorwaarden door op Volgende te klikken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code coverage</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/development_codecov/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:25:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/development_codecov/</guid>
      <description>R CMD check has a large set of generic quality tests on a package. It is impossible to create generic tests that check the content of the package. E.g. does each function return sensible results. However, R CMD check does run a set unit tests. These are small pieces of code written by the package developer which test the output of a specific function under specific circumstances. We highly recommend the testthat framework for writing unit tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading large data files in R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_large_data_files_handling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_large_data_files_handling/</guid>
      <description>Intro R is known to have difficulties handling large data files. Here we will explore some tips that make working with such files in R less painfull.
tl;dr  If you can comfortably work with the entire file in memory, but reading the file is rather slow, consider using the data.table package and read the file with its fread function. If your file does not comfortably fit in memory:  Use sqldf if you have to stick to csv files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read data from INBO databases (SQL Server) with R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_database_access/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_database_access/</guid>
      <description>To query data from a SQL database that is already accessible using MSAccess, such a database is also accessible from R. Here we provide the approach using the package DBI, which is also used by RStudio.1. This package enables the link between R and the (remote) database. After installation of the needed packages (install.packages(c(&amp;quot;DBI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;glue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;))), the packages can be loaded:
library(DBI) library(glue) library(tidyverse) For Windows users, the most important element is to know the so-called DSN (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read data from google sheet</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_google_sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_google_sheets/</guid>
      <description>library(googlesheets) library(dplyr) library(ggplot2) Setup The R package googlesheets provides the functionality to retrieve data from a google sheet. Once the registration as a user is done and the permissions are granted, it enables to read and write to google sheets. Initiation of the authentification can be done with the gs_auth command.
gs_auth() Google will ask to grant the package the permission to access your drive. This token is saved to in a file .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>