<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>databases on INBO Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/categories/databases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in databases on INBO Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/categories/databases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software by INBO: packages for environmentalists and ecologists!</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/inbo_software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/inbo_software/</guid>
      <description>At the Research Institute for Nature and Forest (INBO), we are eager to sustain, promote and develop open-source software that is relevant to biodiversity researchers! This page lists R and Python packages which INBO developed or made a significant contribution to. Several of these packages continue being developed.
Please, feel invited to try out packages! If you encounter a problem or if you have a suggestion, we encourage you to post an issue on the package’s code repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial on how to retrieve data from the INBOVEG database</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_inboveg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_inboveg/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Flemish vegetation database, INBOVEG, is an application developed to provide a repository of relevés and makes the relevés available for future use.
INBOVEG supports different types of recordings: BioHab recordings (protocol of Natura 2000 monitoring) and the classic relevés. The classic relevés can stand alone, be an element of a collection or element of a chain where the linkage is used to give information about the relative position of recording within a series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMM surface waters - quality data</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/vmm_surface_waters_quality_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/vmm_surface_waters_quality_data/</guid>
      <description>OPGELET: deze databank is alleen raadpleegbaar voor INBO-medewerkers, niet voor externen. Externen kunnen gebruik maken van het VMM-geoloket waterkwaliteit.
Het INBO krijgt jaarlijks een (gedeeltelijke) kopie van de waterkwaliteitsdatabank van de Vlaamse Milieumaatschappij (VMM). De kopie omvat fysicochemische metingen en kwaliteitsindexen uit het VMM-meetnet oppervlaktewaters. Deze en andere waterkwaliteitsgevens zijn rechtstreeks opvraagbaar via het VMM-geoloket waterkwaliteit, maar de lokale kopie laat een veel vlottere raadpleging toe wanneer analyse van een groter aantal meetpunten gewenst is.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>