<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>databases on INBO Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/categories/databases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in databases on INBO Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/categories/databases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>(Down)load KNMI, KMI or MOW-HIC data using the inborutils package</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/inborutils_download_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/inborutils_download_data/</guid>
      <description>In this article of the inborutils package it is explained how to use the functions download_knmi_data_hour, read_knmi_data, read_mow_data and read_kmi_data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software by INBO: packages for environmentalists and ecologists!</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/inbo_software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/inbo_software/</guid>
      <description>At the Research Institute for Nature and Forest (INBO), we are eager to sustain, promote and develop open-source software that is relevant to biodiversity researchers! This page lists R and Python packages which INBO developed or made a significant contribution to. Several of these packages continue being developed.
Please, feel free to try out packages! If you encounter a problem or if you have a suggestion, we encourage you to post an issue on the package’s code repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database conventions (MS SQL Server)</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/database_conventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/database_conventions/</guid>
      <description>General  All SQL objects are prefixed, except for databases, schemas, tables and columns and users/logins. The prefixes used depend on the type of object:     Prefix Object type     PK_ primary key constraint   FK_ foreign key constraint   CU_ unique key constraint   CC_ check constraint   CD_ default   IN_ index   VW_ view   TR_ trigger   SQ_ sequence   DR_ database role     choose English or Dutch for the naming of objects and be consistent  Database  The database is created by the DBA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMM surface waters - quality data</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/vmm_surface_waters_quality_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/vmm_surface_waters_quality_data/</guid>
      <description>OPGELET: deze databank is alleen raadpleegbaar voor INBO-medewerkers, niet voor externen. Externen kunnen gebruik maken van het VMM-geoloket waterkwaliteit.
Het INBO krijgt jaarlijks een (gedeeltelijke) kopie van de waterkwaliteitsdatabank van de Vlaamse Milieumaatschappij (VMM). De kopie omvat fysicochemische metingen en kwaliteitsindexen uit het VMM-meetnet oppervlaktewaters. Deze en andere waterkwaliteitsgevens zijn rechtstreeks opvraagbaar via het VMM-geoloket waterkwaliteit, maar de lokale kopie laat een veel vlottere raadpleging toe wanneer analyse van een groter aantal meetpunten gewenst is.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
