<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>INBOmd on INBO Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tags/inbomd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in INBOmd on INBO Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tags/inbomd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of INBO citation style with bibliography managers</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/style_inbo_bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/style_inbo_bibliography/</guid>
      <description>The INBO citation style Most journals, publishers and companies use a specified format for citations and bibliographies. The Research Institute for Nature and Forest (INBO) is no exception.
All bibliography managers provide ways to automate the formatting of citations and bibliographies which greatly facilitates scientific publishing. Depending on the bibliographic manager software, the style formatting rules are stored in specific files. In this tutorial you will learn how to use the INBO citation style in EndNote, Mendeley and Zotero bibliography managers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying the INBO corporate identity to bookdown documents</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_inbomd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_inbomd/</guid>
      <description>During this workshop you learn how to turn a regular Rmarkdown file into a bookdown document using the INBO corporate identity. A lot of tips and trics use plain bookdown. So you can use them with other bookdown output formats.
The slides are available on the INBOmd examples website.
The source code is avalaible in the INBOmd example GitHub repository.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>