<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reports on INBO Tutorials</title>
    <link>/tags/reports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reports on INBO Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/reports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Citations in R Markdown</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r_citations_markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r_citations_markdown/</guid>
      <description>Enter VME mode With the advent of RStudio version 1.4+, working with bibliographies and citing documents in R Markdown has much improved. In this tutorial we focus on best practices to further ease the citation experience when working with R Markdown documents. We also give some guidelines specific to the Research Institute for Nature and Forest.
More general tutorials can be found at the following web pages:
 https://pandoc.org/MANUAL.html#citations https://rstudio.github.io/visual-markdown-editing/citations.html  The latter webpage is part of the documentation about the Visual Markdown Editing (VME) mode that is available since RStudio 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMM surface waters - quality data</title>
      <link>/tutorials/vmm_surface_waters_quality_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/vmm_surface_waters_quality_data/</guid>
      <description>OPGELET: deze databank is alleen raadpleegbaar voor INBO-medewerkers, niet voor externen. Externen kunnen gebruik maken van het VMM-geoloket waterkwaliteit.
Het INBO krijgt jaarlijks een (gedeeltelijke) kopie van de waterkwaliteitsdatabank van de Vlaamse Milieumaatschappij (VMM). De kopie omvat fysicochemische metingen en kwaliteitsindexen uit het VMM-meetnet oppervlaktewaters. Deze en andere waterkwaliteitsgevens zijn rechtstreeks opvraagbaar via het VMM-geoloket waterkwaliteit, maar de lokale kopie laat een veel vlottere raadpleging toe wanneer analyse van een groter aantal meetpunten gewenst is.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
