<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>database on INBO Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tags/database/</link>
    <description>Recent content in database on INBO Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tags/database/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Kerberos authentication for database connection</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/user/user_install_kerberos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/user/user_install_kerberos/</guid>
      <description>Introduction (shamelessly taken from wikipedia)
Kerberos is a computer network authentication protocol that works on the basis of tickets to allow nodes communicating over a non-secure network to prove their identity to one another in a secure manner.
Windows 2000 and later uses Kerberos as its default authentication method. Many UNIX and UNIX-like operating systems, including FreeBSD, Apple&amp;rsquo;s Mac OS X, Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Oracle&amp;rsquo;s Solaris, IBM&amp;rsquo;s AIX and Z/OS, HP&amp;rsquo;s HP-UX and OpenVMS and others, include software for Kerberos authentication of users or services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial on how to retrieve data from the INBOVEG database</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_inboveg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_inboveg/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Flemish vegetation database, INBOVEG, is an application developed to provide a repository of relevés and makes the relevés available for future use.
INBOVEG supports different types of recordings: BioHab recordings (protocol of Natura 2000 monitoring) and the classic relevés. The classic relevés can stand alone, be an element of a collection or element of a chain where the linkage is used to give information about the relative position of recording within a series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMM surface waters - quality data</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/vmm_surface_waters_quality_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/vmm_surface_waters_quality_data/</guid>
      <description>OPGELET: deze databank is alleen raadpleegbaar voor INBO-medewerkers, niet voor externen. Externen kunnen gebruik maken van het VMM-geoloket waterkwaliteit.
Het INBO krijgt jaarlijks een (gedeeltelijke) kopie van de waterkwaliteitsdatabank van de Vlaamse Milieumaatschappij (VMM). De kopie omvat fysicochemische metingen en kwaliteitsindexen uit het VMM-meetnet oppervlaktewaters. Deze en andere waterkwaliteitsgevens zijn rechtstreeks opvraagbaar via het VMM-geoloket waterkwaliteit, maar de lokale kopie laat een veel vlottere raadpleging toe wanneer analyse van een groter aantal meetpunten gewenst is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading large data files in R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_large_data_files_handling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_large_data_files_handling/</guid>
      <description>Intro R is known to have difficulties handling large data files. Here we will explore some tips that make working with such files in R less painfull.
tl;dr  If you can comfortably work with the entire file in memory, but reading the file is rather slow, consider using the data.table package and read the file with its fread function. If your file does not comfortably fit in memory:  Use sqldf if you have to stick to csv files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read data from INBO databases (SQL Server) with R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_database_access/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_database_access/</guid>
      <description>Connection to INBO database Here we provide the approach using the package DBI, which is also used by RStudio.[1]. This package enables the link between R and the (remote) database. After installation of the needed packages (install.packages(c(&amp;quot;DBI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;glue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;))), the packages can be loaded:
library(DBI) library(glue) library(tidyverse) To create a database connection, different approaches are available as explained in the next section:
 Use the dedicated connect_inbo_dbase function in the inbodb package Setup the required parameters yourself Reuse existing registered connections on your computer  Inbodb function To support the connection to INBO databases, a dedicated function is available in the inbodb package, called connect_inbo_dbase.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
