<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>development on INBO Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in development on INBO Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software by INBO: packages for environmentalists and ecologists!</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/inbo_software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/inbo_software/</guid>
      <description>At the Research Institute for Nature and Forest (INBO), we are eager to sustain, promote and develop open-source software that is relevant to biodiversity researchers! This page lists R and Python packages which INBO developed or made a significant contribution to. Several of these packages continue being developed.
Please, feel invited to try out packages! If you encounter a problem or if you have a suggestion, we encourage you to post an issue on the package’s code repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wercker</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/development_wercker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 11:23:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/development_wercker/</guid>
      <description>Set up continuous integration with Wercker There are 2 major steps to set up continuous integration:
 create a wercker.yml file in the package add the application (package) to Wercker.com  To be able to add a package to Wercker, one must have administrator rights on the package repository on Github.
The Wercker test environment can only be set up if the file wercker.yml is commited to the repository, but Wercker is triggered to start checking when the application is added to wercker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code coverage</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/development_codecov/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:25:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/development_codecov/</guid>
      <description>R CMD check has a large set of generic quality tests on a package. It is impossible to create generic tests that check the content of the package. E.g. does each function return sensible results. However, R CMD check does run a set unit tests. These are small pieces of code written by the package developer which test the output of a specific function under specific circumstances. We highly recommend the testthat framework for writing unit tests.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>