<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>r on INBO Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in r on INBO Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software by INBO: packages for environmentalists and ecologists!</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/inbo_software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/inbo_software/</guid>
      <description>At the Research Institute for Nature and Forest (INBO), we are eager to sustain, promote and develop open-source software that is relevant to biodiversity researchers! This page lists R and Python packages which INBO developed or made a significant contribution to. Several of these packages continue being developed.
Please, feel invited to try out packages! If you encounter a problem or if you have a suggestion, we encourage you to post an issue on the package’s code repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read data from Google sheets</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_google_sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_google_sheets/</guid>
      <description>googlesheets4 The R package googlesheets4 provides the functionality to read and write data from a Google sheet.
This package is very well documented, so we just have to provide you with the right links:
 read sheets write sheets  There are also two specific in-depth articles: one about reading and one about writing sheets.
A complete list of vignettes can be found in the Articles page.
googlesheets4 vs googlesheets The package googlesheets4 is the follower of googlesheets which doesn&#39;t work anymore as it is built on the outdated Sheets v3 API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye PROJ.4 strings! How to specify a coordinate reference system in R?</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_crs_coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_crs_coding/</guid>
      <description>Coordinate reference systems: minimal background What? A coordinate reference system (CRS) – also called spatial reference system (SRS) – is what you need if you want to interpret numeric coordinates as actual point locations with reference to the Earth. Two types of coordinate reference system exist: geodetic and projected CRSes. The former serve only to locate coordinates relative to a 3D model of the Earth surface, while the latter add a projection to generate coordinates on a 2D map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use open raster file formats in R: GeoTIFF &amp; GeoPackage</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_standards_raster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_standards_raster/</guid>
      <description>General note: the way the raster package handles coordinate reference systems has just recently (at the time of writing) become compliant with recent GDAL 3 and PROJ &amp;gt;= 6 versions. At the time of writing, it was necessary to use the current development version of raster (link). During the current transition period of supporting both old and new PROJ/GDAL, you may get a decent portion of proj4string-related warnings when running the below code (as seen below), but you can safely ignore them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming spatial objects</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_transform_crs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_transform_crs/</guid>
      <description>General note: migration to the more actively developed sf package is currently advised by the sp maintainer. The sp package, used in this tutorial, is still maintained in order to support the newest versions of the GDAL and PROJ backends.
Sometimes we have a layer in one coordinate reference system (CRS) and need to transform it into another coordinate reference system. The first thing we need to do is identifying both coordinate reference systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed model formulation of a paired t-test</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_paired_t_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_paired_t_test/</guid>
      <description>What you will learn In this tutorial we explain the analogy between the paired t-test and the corresponding mixed model formulation.
Used packages library(knitr) library(lme4) library(tidyr) library(broom) library(DHARMa) Data  plot: identifies paired measurements response: measurement values treatment: identifies two treatments (a and b)  set.seed(124) paired_data &amp;lt;- data.frame( plot = rep(1:10, 2), response = c(rnorm(10), rnorm(10, 3, 1.5)), treatment = rep(c(&amp;#34;a&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;b&amp;#34;), each = 10) ) paired_data$treatment &amp;lt;- as.factor(paired_data$treatment) paired_data$plot &amp;lt;- as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Same variable in fixed and random effects</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_fixed_random/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_fixed_random/</guid>
      <description>Used packages library(ggplot2) ## Warning: package &#39;ggplot2&#39; was built under R version 4.0.2  library(lme4) ## Loading required package: Matrix  Dummy data For the sake of this demontration we use a very simple dataset with a very high signal versus noise ratio. Let’s look at a simple timeseries with multiple observations per timepoint.
set.seed(213354) n.year &amp;lt;- 30 n.replicate &amp;lt;- 10 sd.noise &amp;lt;- 0.1 dataset &amp;lt;- expand.grid( Replicate = seq_len(n.replicate), Year = seq_len(n.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using WFS service in R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_wfs_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_wfs_services/</guid>
      <description>What is WFS? In computing, the Open Geospatial Consortium (OGC) Web Feature Service (WFS) Interface Standard provides an interface allowing requests for geographical features across the web using platform-independent calls. One can think of geographical features as the “source code” behind a map, whereas the Web Mapping Service (WMS) interface or online tiled mapping portals like Google Maps return only an image, which end-users cannot edit or spatially analyze.
The standard output format for reading or downloading data from a WFS is the XML-based Geography Markup Language (GML), but other formats like shapefiles or geojson are also available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use open vector file formats in R: GeoPackage &amp; GeoJSON</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_standards_vector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_standards_vector/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial uses a few basic functions from the dplyr and sf packages. While only a few functions are used, you can use the previous hyperlinks to access the tutorials (vignettes) of these packages for more functions and information.
options(stringsAsFactors = FALSE) library(tidyverse) library(sf) library(inborutils) You will find a bit more background about ‘why and what’, regarding the considered open standards, in a separate post on this website.
In short, the GeoPackage and GeoJSON formats are ideal for exchange, publication, interoperability &amp;amp; durability and to open science in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet some popular open geospatial standards!</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/geospatial_standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/geospatial_standards/</guid>
      <description>Some inspiration for this post came from the beautiful books of Lovelace et al. (2020), Pebesma &amp;amp; Bivand (2019) and Hijmans (2019), and from various websites.
Why use open standards?  Open file standards ease collaboration, portability and compatibility between users, machines and applications. Their (file) structure is fully documented.  Consequently, scientists and programmers can build new software / packages and make innovations that use these standards, while maintaining interoperability with existing applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification and visualisation of estimates and their uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_effectclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_effectclass/</guid>
      <description>Here are the slides of a presentation about the effectclass package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Match scientific names with the GBIF Backbone Taxonomy</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_gbif_name_matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_gbif_name_matching/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will explain how you can match a list of scientific names against the GBIF backbone taxonomy.
It is important that you have the most recent version of inborutils installed and available:
remotes::install_github(&amp;#34;inbo/inborutils&amp;#34;) # install inborutils library(tidyverse) # To do datascience library(rgbif) # To lookup names in the GBIF backbone taxonomy library(inborutils) # To wrap GBIF API data library(knitr) Read data file containing the scientific names Read file containing the scientific names you want to check against the GBIF taxonomic backbone:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make spatial joins (point in polygon)?</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_point_in_polygon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_point_in_polygon/</guid>
      <description>library(R.utils) library(rgdal) library(tidyverse) library(leaflet) library(sp) library(sf) library(rgbif) library(DBI) What we want to do In this short tutorial, we explore various options to deal with the situation where we have (1) a spatially referenced GIS file with polygons and (2) a spatially referenced set of points that overlaps with the GIS polygons.
Typically, both data sources contain information (apart from the spatial locations) that needs to be related to each other in some way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying the INBO corporate identity to bookdown documents</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_inbomd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_inbomd/</guid>
      <description>During this workshop you learn how to turn a regular Rmarkdown file into a bookdown document using the INBO corporate identity. A lot of tips and trics use plain bookdown. So you can use them with other bookdown output formats.
The slides are available on the INBOmd examples website.
The source code is avalaible in the INBOmd example GitHub repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R voor beginners</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_beginners/</guid>
      <description>Doel van de cursus Hoe maak je van je ingezamelde gegevens een reproduceerbare analyse, visualisatie en rapportage, gebruik makend van de software R en Rstudio.
 Rstudio kunnen gebruiken (Les 1a) Commando&#39;s uitvoeren vanuit een script (Les 1b) Externe databestanden inlezen in R (Les 2a) Gegevens visualiseren (ggplot2) (Les 2b) Data manipuleren in een gewenste vorm (dplyr) (Les 3) Reproduceerbaar analyserapport maken (Rmarkdown) + algemene vragen (Les 4)  Bovenstaande topics worden gecombineerd in een opleiding van 4 workshops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INLA workshops</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_inla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_inla/</guid>
      <description>These workshops are a follow-up of the course on &amp;ldquo;Spatial, temporal and spatial-temporal models using R-INLA&amp;rdquo; by Alain Zuur and Elena Ieno (Highland Statistics Ltd.). The main goal is the get people using R-INLA with their own data in a workshop setting so they can tap into the knowledge of others. The workshops are not a copy of the Highstat course but elaborate certain topics. We also introduce the inlatools and inlabru.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headers and navigation in R code</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_script_sections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_script_sections/</guid>
      <description>Introduction R code can become elaborate and consequently unclear or difficult to navigate. Yet, it is possible to introduce headers and navigate through them.
Creating sections manually To create a header of a section, different methods can be applied. Any comment line which includes at least four trailing dashes (-), equal signs (=), or hash tags (#) automatically creates a code section.
# 1. Header 1 #### # 2. Header 2 ---- # 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s create an interactive map!</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_create_leaflet_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_create_leaflet_map/</guid>
      <description>General note: migration to the more actively developed sf package is currently advised by the sp maintainer. The sp package, used in this tutorial, is still maintained in order to support the newest versions of the GDAL and PROJ backends.
Introduction The required packages are leaflet and sp.
library(leaflet) library(sp) Dummy data Let’s create a dumy data.frame to play around, i.e. the three locations of INBO:
names &amp;lt;- c(&amp;#34;VAC HT&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Geraardsbergen&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Linkebeek&amp;#34;) lat &amp;lt;- c(50.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using `%&gt;%` pipes in R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_tidyverse_piping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_tidyverse_piping/</guid>
      <description>library(dplyr) How to use piping in R Normally, you would do this:
head(mtcars) ## mpg cyl disp hp drat wt qsec vs am gear carb ## Mazda RX4 21.0 6 160 110 3.90 2.620 16.46 0 1 4 4 ## Mazda RX4 Wag 21.0 6 160 110 3.90 2.875 17.02 0 1 4 4 ## Datsun 710 22.8 4 108 93 3.85 2.320 18.61 1 1 4 1 ## Hornet 4 Drive 21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wercker</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/development_wercker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 11:23:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/development_wercker/</guid>
      <description>Set up continuous integration with Wercker There are 2 major steps to set up continuous integration:
 create a wercker.yml file in the package add the application (package) to Wercker.com  To be able to add a package to Wercker, one must have administrator rights on the package repository on Github.
The Wercker test environment can only be set up if the file wercker.yml is commited to the repository, but Wercker is triggered to start checking when the application is added to wercker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using WMS service in R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_wms_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 12:09:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_wms_services/</guid>
      <description>WMS stands for Web Map Service. The service provides prerendered tiles at different scales. This makes it useful to include them as background images in maps.
wms_grb links to the WMS of the GRB-basiskaart, the Flemish cadastral map. It depicts land parcels, buildings, watercourses, roads and railroads.
wms_ortho contains a mosaic of recent orthophotos made during the winter. The layer Ortho contains the images, the layer Vliegdagcontour detail on the time when the pictures were taken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data wrangling with tidyverse</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_tidyverse_info/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 14:14:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_tidyverse_info/</guid>
      <description>Real life datasources seldom provide data in exactly the format you need for the analysis. Hence most of the time you need to manipulate the data after reading it into R. There are several ways to do this, each with their pros and cons. We highly recommend the tidyverse collection of packages. The command library(tidyverse) will actually load the following packages: ggplot2, dplyr, tidyr, readr, purrr, tibble, stringr and forecats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Styleguide R code</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/styleguide_r_code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 16:01:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/styleguide_r_code/</guid>
      <description>Scope This style guide is a recommendation for all R code written for the Research Institute for Nature and Forest (INBO). The goal of this style guide is twofold. First of all applying the guidelines will result in readable code. Secondly, it is much easier to work together on code when everyone is using the same guidelines. It is likely that applying these guidelines will have consequences on the current style used by many R users at INBO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rstudio installation</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/user/user_install_rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 15:43:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/user/user_install_rstudio/</guid>
      <description>Na de eerste installatie  Start Rstudio Kies in het menu Tools -&amp;gt; Global Options In het tabblad General  Pas de Default working directory aan naar de locatie waar je R versie staat (C:/Program Files/R/R-4.x.y) 1 Restore .RData into workspace at startup: uitvinken Save workspace to.RData on exit: Never   In het tabblad Code  Subtab Editing  Insert spaces for tab: aanvinken Tab width: 2 Soft-wrap R source files: aanvinken   Subtab Saving  Default text encoding: UTF-8   Subtab Diagnostics  Alles aanvinken     In het tabblad Appearance  Stel in naar eigen smaak   In het tabblad Packages  CRAN mirror: wijzigen naar Global (CDN) - RStudio   In het tabblad Sweave  Weave Rnw files using: knitr Typeset LaTeX into PDF using: XeLaTex   Klik op OK en herstart RStudio  Configuratie van RStudio na een upgrade van R  Start RStudio Kies in het menu Tools -&amp;gt; Global Options Indien niet de laatste versie vermeld staat bij R version: klik op Change om het aan te passen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R language installation</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/user/user_install_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 15:43:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/user/user_install_r/</guid>
      <description>Na de eerste installatie Bij een nieuwe R installatie hoeft de gebruiker geen bijkomende stappen te ondernemen.
Na elke upgrade Voor onderstaande instructies uit telkens een nieuwe R versie geïnstalleerd werd. Je kan dit, indien gewenst, ook frequenter uitvoeren.
Windows  Zorg dat de computer verbonden is met het internet. Zorg dat er geen enkele R sessie actief is op de computer. Start R x64 x.y.z via het menu Start &amp;gt; Alle programma&#39;s &amp;gt; R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Desktop installation</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:30:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_rstudio/</guid>
      <description>De installatiebestanden voor de stabiele versies zijn beschikbaar via http://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/. De preview versie is beschikbaar via https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/preview/
Windows Nieuwe installatie en upgrade van RStudio RStudio upgraden doe je door de nieuwe versie te installeren over de oude.
 Zorg dat eerst R geïnstalleerd is. Voer het 64-bit installatiebestand uit. Klik Ja. Welkom bij de installatie: klik op volgende. Geef de doelmap en klik op volgende. Je mag de standaard gebruiken. Klik op installeren.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rtools installation</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_rtools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:30:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_rtools/</guid>
      <description>Windows Installatie en upgrade De installatiebestanden zijn beschikbaar via cloud.r-project.org. Kies de 64-bit versie van de installer.
Bij een upgrade dient eerst de vorige versie te worden verwijderd.
 Klik Ja. Kies C:\rtools40 (standaard) als installatiemap en klik Next. Laat alles aangevinkt en klik Next. Klik Install. Klik Finish. Wijzing PATH naar PATH=&amp;quot;${RTOOLS40_HOME}\usr\bin;${PATH}&amp;quot;. Start R en controleer of Sys.which(&amp;quot;make&amp;quot;) verwijst naar &amp;quot;C:\\rtools40\\usr\\bin\\make.exe&amp;quot;.  Afwijkingen t.o.v. default installatie  Wijzig de systeemvariabele PATH naar PATH=&amp;quot;${RTOOLS40_HOME}\usr\bin;${PATH}&amp;quot;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:25:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/installation/administrator/admin_install_r/</guid>
      <description>Windows Installatiebestand beschikbaar via cloud.r-project.org
In de onderstaande tekst moet je in R-4.x.y zowel x als y vervangen door een cijfer om zo het huidige versienummer te krijgen. Dus voor versie R-4.0.0 is x = 0 en y = 0.
Nieuwe installatie van R  Voer het bestand R-4.x.y-win.exe uit. Kies Nederlands als taal voor de installatie en klik op OK. klik op Volgende. Aanvaard de licentievoorwaarden door op Volgende te klikken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code coverage</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/development_codecov/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:25:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/development_codecov/</guid>
      <description>R CMD check has a large set of generic quality tests on a package. It is impossible to create generic tests that check the content of the package. E.g. does each function return sensible results. However, R CMD check does run a set unit tests. These are small pieces of code written by the package developer which test the output of a specific function under specific circumstances. We highly recommend the testthat framework for writing unit tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading large data files in R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_large_data_files_handling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_large_data_files_handling/</guid>
      <description>Intro R is known to have difficulties handling large data files. Here we will explore some tips that make working with such files in R less painfull.
tl;dr  If you can comfortably work with the entire file in memory, but reading the file is rather slow, consider using the data.table package and read the file with its fread function. If your file does not comfortably fit in memory:  Use sqldf if you have to stick to csv files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read data from INBO databases (SQL Server) with R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_database_access/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_database_access/</guid>
      <description>Connection to INBO database Here we provide the approach using the package DBI, which is also used by RStudio.[1]. This package enables the link between R and the (remote) database. After installation of the needed packages (install.packages(c(&amp;quot;DBI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;glue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;))), the packages can be loaded:
library(DBI) library(glue) library(tidyverse) To create a database connection, different approaches are available as explained in the next section:
 Use the dedicated connect_inbo_dbase function in the inbodb package Setup the required parameters yourself Reuse existing registered connections on your computer  Inbodb function To support the connection to INBO databases, a dedicated function is available in the inbodb package, called connect_inbo_dbase.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>