<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>zotero on INBO Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tags/zotero/</link>
    <description>Recent content in zotero on INBO Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tags/zotero/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Citations in R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_citations_markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_citations_markdown/</guid>
      <description>Enter VME mode With the advent of RStudio version 1.4+, working with bibliographies and citing documents in R Markdown has much improved. In this tutorial we focus on best practices to further ease the citation experience when working with R Markdown documents. We also give some guidelines specific to the Research Institute for Nature and Forest.
More general tutorials can be found at the following web pages:
 https://pandoc.org/MANUAL.html#citations https://rstudio.github.io/visual-markdown-editing/citations.html  The latter webpage is part of the documentation about the Visual Markdown Editing (VME) mode that is available since RStudio 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of INBO citation style with bibliography managers</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/style_inbo_bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/style_inbo_bibliography/</guid>
      <description>The INBO citation style Most journals, publishers and companies use a specified format for citations and bibliographies. The Research Institute for Nature and Forest (INBO) is no exception.
All bibliography managers provide ways to automate the formatting of citations and bibliographies which greatly facilitates scientific publishing. Depending on the bibliographic manager software, the style formatting rules are stored in specific files. In this tutorial you will learn how to use the INBO citation style in EndNote, Mendeley and Zotero bibliography managers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
