<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>statistics on INBO Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/categories/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statistics on INBO Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/categories/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software by INBO: packages for environmentalists and ecologists!</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/inbo_software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/inbo_software/</guid>
      <description>At the Research Institute for Nature and Forest (INBO), we are eager to sustain, promote and develop open-source software that is relevant to biodiversity researchers! This page lists R and Python packages which INBO developed or made a significant contribution to. Several of these packages continue being developed.
Please, feel invited to try out packages! If you encounter a problem or if you have a suggestion, we encourage you to post an issue on the package’s code repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed model formulation of a paired t-test</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_paired_t_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_paired_t_test/</guid>
      <description>What you will learn In this tutorial we explain the analogy between the paired t-test and the corresponding mixed model formulation.
Used packages library(knitr) library(lme4) library(tidyr) library(broom) library(DHARMa) Data  plot: identifies paired measurements response: measurement values treatment: identifies two treatments (a and b)  set.seed(124) paired_data &amp;lt;- data.frame( plot = rep(1:10, 2), response = c(rnorm(10), rnorm(10, 3, 1.5)), treatment = rep(c(&amp;#34;a&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;b&amp;#34;), each = 10) ) paired_data$treatment &amp;lt;- as.factor(paired_data$treatment) paired_data$plot &amp;lt;- as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Same variable in fixed and random effects</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_fixed_random/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_fixed_random/</guid>
      <description>Used packages library(ggplot2) ## Warning: package &#39;ggplot2&#39; was built under R version 4.0.2  library(lme4) ## Loading required package: Matrix  Dummy data For the sake of this demontration we use a very simple dataset with a very high signal versus noise ratio. Let’s look at a simple timeseries with multiple observations per timepoint.
n.year &amp;lt;- 30 n.replicate &amp;lt;- 10 sd.noise &amp;lt;- 0.1 dataset &amp;lt;- expand.grid( Replicate = seq_len(n.replicate), Year = seq_len(n.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification and visualisation of estimates and their uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_effectclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_effectclass/</guid>
      <description>Here are the slides of a presentation about the effectclass package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INLA workshops</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_inla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_inla/</guid>
      <description>These workshops are a follow-up of the course on &amp;ldquo;Spatial, temporal and spatial-temporal models using R-INLA&amp;rdquo; by Alain Zuur and Elena Ieno (Highland Statistics Ltd.). The main goal is the get people using R-INLA with their own data in a workshop setting so they can tap into the knowledge of others. The workshops are not a copy of the Highstat course but elaborate certain topics. We also introduce the inlatools and inlabru.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>