<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hansvancalster on INBO Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/authors/hansvancalster/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hansvancalster on INBO Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/authors/hansvancalster/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using WFS services in R</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_wfs_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_wfs_services/</guid>
      <description>What is WFS? In computing, the Open Geospatial Consortium (OGC) Web Feature Service (WFS) Interface Standard provides an interface allowing requests for geographical features across the web using platform-independent calls. One can think of geographical features as the “source code” behind a map, whereas the Web Mapping Service (WMS) interface or online tiled mapping portals like Google Maps return only an image, which end-users cannot edit or spatially analyze.
The standard output format for reading or downloading data from a WFS is the XML-based Geography Markup Language (GML), but other formats like shapefiles or geojson are also available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git and GitHub Authentication on Windows</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/git_authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/git_authentication/</guid>
      <description>Before we start This tutorial assumes you have a GitHub account, and have Git, R and RStudio installed on your system. The purpose of this tutorial is to make clear recommendations about authentication for employees at INBO who use Git version control in their workflows. The guidelines here are meant for people who use Git and GitHub in RStudio, but the general principles can be applied to other software too (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citations in R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_citations_markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_citations_markdown/</guid>
      <description>Enter VME mode With the advent of RStudio version 1.4+, working with bibliographies and citing documents in R Markdown has much improved. In this tutorial we focus on best practices to further ease the citation experience when working with R Markdown documents. We also give some guidelines specific to the Research Institute for Nature and Forest.
More general tutorials can be found at the following web pages:
 https://pandoc.org/MANUAL.html#citations https://rstudio.github.io/visual-markdown-editing/citations.html  The latter webpage is part of the documentation about the Visual Markdown Editing (VME) mode that is available since RStudio 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics courses @ INBO!</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/inbo_stats_courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/articles/inbo_stats_courses/</guid>
      <description>During the course of the years, we have taught many statistics courses at the Research Institute for Nature and Forest (INBO), both for scientists and technicians. Most of these courses have been developed and taught in-house. Some (mostly advanced) courses were taught in-house by external teachers.
While we do plan to periodically repeat these courses for new employees and as a refresher, the course material can always be consulted and used for self-teaching or as a reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of INBO citation style with bibliography managers</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/style_inbo_bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/style_inbo_bibliography/</guid>
      <description>The INBO citation style Most journals, publishers and companies use a specified format for citations and bibliographies. The Research Institute for Nature and Forest (INBO) is no exception.
All bibliography managers provide ways to automate the formatting of citations and bibliographies which greatly facilitates scientific publishing. Depending on the bibliographic manager software, the style formatting rules are stored in specific files. In this tutorial you will learn how to use the INBO citation style in EndNote, Mendeley and Zotero bibliography managers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>inbodb: How to retrieve data from the INBOVEG database</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/vignette_inbodb_get_data_inboveg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/vignette_inbodb_get_data_inboveg/</guid>
      <description>See the vignette/tutorial at https://inbo.github.io/inbodb/articles/get_data_inboveg.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed model formulation of a paired t-test</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_paired_t_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/r_paired_t_test/</guid>
      <description>What you will learn In this tutorial we explain the analogy between the paired t-test and the corresponding mixed model formulation.
Used packages library(knitr) library(lme4) library(tidyr) library(broom) library(DHARMa) Data  plot: identifies paired measurements response: measurement values treatment: identifies two treatments (a and b)  set.seed(124) paired_data &amp;lt;- data.frame( plot = rep(1:10, 2), response = c(rnorm(10), rnorm(10, 3, 1.5)), treatment = rep(c(&amp;#34;a&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;b&amp;#34;), each = 10) ) paired_data$treatment &amp;lt;- as.factor(paired_data$treatment) paired_data$plot &amp;lt;- as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Styleguide new git repositories</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/styleguide_repos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/styleguide_repos/</guid>
      <description>Naming   Use lowercase for repository, directory, and file names. For R-related files, use uppercase R.
 https://github.com/inbo/data-publication ../tutorials/gis/leaflet-R.Rmd    Use dash (-) to separate words in directory and file names. Don&amp;rsquo;t use underscores.
 .../datasets/bird-tracking-gull-occurrences/mapping/dwc-occurrence.sql    Avoid the use of dash (-) in the name of repositories that you intend for R package development (it is OK to use a dash in repository names for other purposes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make spatial joins (point in polygon)?</title>
      <link>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_point_in_polygon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://inbo.github.io/tutorials/tutorials/spatial_point_in_polygon/</guid>
      <description>library(R.utils) library(rgdal) library(tidyverse) library(leaflet) library(sp) library(sf) library(rgbif) library(DBI) What we want to do In this short tutorial, we explore various options to deal with the situation where we have (1) a spatially referenced GIS file with polygons and (2) a spatially referenced set of points that overlaps with the GIS polygons.
Typically, both data sources contain information (apart from the spatial locations) that needs to be related to each other in some way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
